It's a filthy job getting to the top, but someone's got to do it.
Filth is a crime, drama, comedy film directed by Jon S. Baird.
A bigoted junkie cop suffering from borderline personality disorder and drug
addiction manipulates and hallucinates his way in a bid to secure promotion.
Bruce, played by James McAvoy.
Lennox, played by Jamie Bell.
Bladesey, played by Eddie Marsan.
Drummond, played by Imogen Poots.
Gillman, played by Brian McCardie.
Inglis, played by Emun Elliott.
Filth is a 2013 psychological black comedy crime
thriller film written and directed by Jon S.
Baird, based on Irvine Welsh's 1998 novel Filth.
The film was released on 27 September 2013 in Scotland, 4 October 2013 elsewhere in the
United Kingdom and in Ireland, and on 30 May 2014 in the United States.
It stars James McAvoy, Jamie Bell, and Jim Broadbent.
Filth marked the final film role of David Soul, in a cameo role.
Set in Edinburgh, the film follows a misanthropic Detective Sergeant investigating a murder
case, beset with mental health problems following the end of his marriage.
He suffers from borderline personality disorder, feelings of guilt over the
death of his brother and (eventually) suicidal ideation.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
detective, cocaine, investigation, manipulation.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.